Guide to the Southeast Women's Employment Coalition Records, 1868-1991 bulk (1981-1990)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Southeast Women's Employment Coalition records 1868-1991, bulk 1981-1990
Southeast Women's Employment Coalition
103.5 linear feet Extent: 62,100 items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Durham, North Carolina 27708-0185
RL.01272
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Individuals have a legally enforceable right to privacy and the right to suppress release of information obtained through the employer-employee relationship. The use of names of living individuals involved in this kind of relationship is prohibited without the employee's consent. Therefore the release of information contained in the Personnel Files Series may give rise to liability (e.g. for defamation or invasion of privacy). Duke University assumes no responsibility for infringement of literary property rights and copyrights, or for liability to any person for defamation or invasion of privacy. RESTRICTION: Before a patron may use this series a disclaimer form must be signed.
In addition, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Southeast Women's Employment Coalition Records (1868-1991) were donated to the Special Collections Department in 1991 by Margo Smith.
Historical Note
1979 Founded in Tennessee as a fusion of fourteen regional organizations
1980 Began Leadership Development Program to assist grass-roots organizing Filed administrative complaints with the United States Department of Labor and the United States Department of Transportation
1981 Implemented road construction job recruitment projects, involving the Women's Asphalt Alliance
1982 Began Education and Research Project, which collected and circulated economic data providing employment statistics for women workers Began first cycle of leadership training Lobbied successfully to amend Federal Highway Act and Surface Transportation Act of 1982 Headquarters moved to Lexington, Ky.
1983 Began Women's Opportunity in Road Construction (WORC) Project Assisted in filing successful class action suit against the Missouri Highways and Transportation Department
1984 Sponsored "Women Organizing Women" Conference Launched Department of Transportation investigation of state hiring and employment practices Women's Opportunity in Road Construction produced a statistical report profiling state Department Of Transportation hiring practices First fellowships awarded by Leadership Development Program for work with Blue Collar Women organization
1985 Established Southern Dollars Campaign
1987 Launched Tourism Project in conjunction with Economics Research Project and sponsored a meeting of fifty women Formed Women's Opportunity in Road Construction Strategy Committee and compiled Women's Opportunity in Road Construction Fact Pack Lobbied to increase the federal minimum wage
1990 Headquarters moved to Atlanta, Ga.
1991, March 1 Offices closed due to lack of funding
Collection Overview
The Southeast Women's Employment Coalition Records (SWEC) span the period 1868 to 1991 with the bulk dating from 1981 to 1990. The multiracial, regional organization was founded chiefly to expand employment opportunities for women in the rural South. Correspondence, financial records, reports, printed material, personnel files, photographs, audiovisual material, writings, meeting minutes, and conference papers comprise the majority of the collection. Well documented are the Southeast Women's Employment Coalition's efforts: to provide leadership training for women; to encourage women to apply for nontraditional jobs, for example through its Women's Opportunity in Road Construction (WORC) Project; to promote women's employment in the tourism industry; to evaluate economic, social and political trends affecting women in the South such as child care, comparable worth, and nontraditional jobs for women; and to establish ties with other organizations seeking to improve women's economic status. Administrative concerns relating to the Southeast Women's Employment Coalition, including personnel, financial, and organizational issues are also well described. Represented extensively are their efforts to raise money from private foundations and businesses. Organizations highlighted in the collection include Public Affairs Research and Communications, Inc. and the Women's Technical Assistance Project. In general, information concerning these topics and organizations is scattered throughout the collection.
Leadership training for women, for example through workshops and conferences, is documented by the Research Director's Files Series, Writings Series, Project Files Series, Conference Files Series, Printed Material Series, Office Files Series, and Audiovisual Series. In addition, there is information on efforts to encourage women's employment in highway construction and tourism through congressional hearings and writings in the Research Director's Files Series, General Files Series, Project Files Series, Highways Projects Files Series, Pictures Series, and Audiovisual Series.
Papers evaluating the economic, social, and political trends affecting women in the South such as child care issues and salaries are found in the Research Director's Files Series, Office Files Series, Writings Series, General Files Series, Project Files Series, Highways Projects Files Series, Subject Files Series, Conference Files Series, Organizations Series, Printed Material Series, and Audiovisual Series. Attempts to establish ties with other organizations are found in the Research Director's Files Series, Office Files Series, Financial Papers Series, General Files Series, Proposals Series, Highways Projects Files Series, Conference Files Series, Organizations Series, and Audiovisual Series. The organizations include the Restaurant Employees Association of Lexington, Ky., Tradeswomen, Inc., and Women for Economic Justice.
Administrative concerns relating to the Southeast Women's Employment Coalition are addressed by the Research Director's Files Series, Board and Staff Meetings Series, Office Files Series, Correspondence Series, Financial Papers Series, Personnel Files Series, General Files Series, Proposals Series, Project Files Series, and Audiovisual Series. Information pertaining to Public Affairs Research and Communications, Inc. and the Women's Technical Assistance Project are included in the Proposals Series, Office Files Series, General Files Series, Organizations Series, and the Project Files Series.
Subject Headings
Southeast Women's Employment Coalition; Women's Opportunity in Road Construction Project; Women's Technical Assistance Project; Public Affairs Research and Communications, Inc.; Rural women -- Employment -- Southern States; Rural women -- Southern States -- Economic conditions; Rural women -- Southern States -- Social conditions; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Southern States; Rural women -- Southern States -- Social networks; Leadership -- Study and teaching; Road construction industry -- United States; Tourist trade -- Southern States -- Employees; Rural women -- Training of -- Southern States
Contents of Collection
- Research Director's Files Series, 1934-1988, undated (bulk 1981-1987)
  Correspondence, writings and speeches, bibliographies, brochures, newsletters, and catalogs. Arranged in alphabetical order by topic.
  - Agricultural land ownership: (Box 1)
    - Agricultural policy, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Black land loss, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
    - Land ownership and use, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - Political economy of hunger, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Agricultural workers and women: (Box 1)
    - Farm laborers and unions, 1981-1984 (Box 1)
    - Women on farms, 1982-1983, undated (Box 1)
  - Bibliographies: (Box 1)
    - Bibliography/Publications international issues, 1980-1985, undated (Box 1)
    - Women, 1976-1986, undated (Box 1)
    - Women of color, 1982-1986, undated (Box 1)
  - Book lists, publishers, 1980-1987, undated (Box 1)
  - Child care and parental leave: (Box 1)
    - Child care, 1977-1988, undated (Box 1)
    - Parental leave, 1987, undated (Box 1)
  - Data sources: (Box 1)
    - Computer: General information, 1986, undated (Box 1)
    - Data Banks: Industries, employment, 1983-1986, undated (Box 1)
    - Notes, tips, references, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - Demographic trends: (Box 1)
    - 1975-1983, undated (Box 1)
    - Demographic data: Census, 1980-1985 (Box 1)
    - Fertility/Teen pregnancy, 1986, undated (Box 1)
    - Infant mortality, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Economic development: (Box 1)
    - 1983-1987, undated (Box 1)
    - Cooperatives, 1982-1985 (Box 1)
    - Racism in economic development, 1983, undated (Box 1)
    - Rural development strategies, 1977-1985, undated (Box 1)
    - Small business development, 1982-1986, undated (Box 1)
    - State policies: (Box 1)
      - Industrial recruitment, 1986, undated (Box 1)
      - General information, undated (Box 1)
      - Tax policies, 1986, undated (Box 1)
  - Economy: Reaganomics: (Box 1)
    - Reagan budget issues, 1981-1987, undated (Box 1)
    - Taxes and reaganomics, 1979-1986 (Box 1)
  - Educational resources: Films, slide tapes, 1934-1985, undated (Box 1)
  - Electoral politics: (Box 1)
    - Electoral trends, 1986, undated (Box 1)
    - Gender gap, 1983-1984, undated (Box 1)
  - Employee benefits: Pensions and retirement, 1980-1988 (Box 1)
  - Employment discrimination: (Box 1)
    - Contract compliance, 1981-1986, undated (Box 1)
    - General, 1978-1988, undated (Box 1)
    - Pregnancy discrimination, 1978-1981, undated (Box 1)
  - Employment structure and workforce: (Box 1)
    - Immigration, 1975-1983 (Box 1)
    - General trends, 1978-1986, undated (Box 1)
  - Fact sheets: (Box 2)
    - 1978-1984, undated (Box 2)
    - Southeast Women's Employment Coalition, undated (Box 2)
  - Government sources: (Box 2)
    - Census data: Guides, critiques, 1982-1987, undated (Box 2)
    - United States Government Printing Office publications, 1976-1986, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - High technology: (Box 2)
    - Economics: (Box 2)
      - High technology: General, 1980-1987 (Box 2)
      - Location decisions and implications, 1981-1984, undated (Box 2)
    - Labor implications: Workers and the labor process, 1981-1985, undated (Box 2)
  - Labor: Current: (Box 2)
    - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations: Politics and organizing, 1979-1986 (Box 2)
    - Coalition of Labor Union Women: Women in unions, 1974-1982, undated (Box 2)
    - Collective bargaining trends, 1982-1988, undated (Box 2)
    - Immigration, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Labor legislation, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Strikes, 1985-1988 (Box 2)
  - Logo/Graphics: Logo designs and correspondence, 1986, undated (Box 2)
  - Organization mailing lists: (Box 2)
    - Academics and women's centers, 1982-1986, undated (Box 2)
    - Government and policymaking, 1986, undated (Box 2)
    - Journals, 1986, undated (Box 2)
    - Progressives, 1981-1986, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Religious organizations, 1983-1986, undated (Box 2)
    - Research project/contact lists regarding Fillmore, 1982-1983, undated (Box 2)
  - Participatory research: (Box 2)
    - Articles and sources, 1981-1983, undated (Box 2)
    - Group, 1982-1984, undated (Box 2)
    - Workshop and discussion notes, 1983-1984, undated (Box 2)
  - Poultry industry, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Poverty and welfare: (Box 2)
    - Black poverty, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
    - Feminization of poverty, 1979-1986, undated (Box 2)
    - Poverty: General analyses, 1984-1988, undated (Box 2)
    - Poverty statistics, 1978-1986, undated (Box 2)
    - Welfare reform/workfare, 1976-1988 (Box 2)
    - Working poor, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Proposals: (Box 2)
    - Ford Foundation: (Box 2)
      - 1983-1985, (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1982-1987, undated (Box 2)
      - Ford trustee visit, 1987, undated (Box 3)
      - Reports and notes, 1982-1987, undated (Box 3)
      - Women and employment (Ford submittal), 1982 (Box 3)
    - General Support proposal: (Box 3)
      - Levi Strauss (Reports on Organization Development Grant), 1983-1986 (Box 3)
      - Mary Reynolds Babcock, 1984-1985, undated (Box 3)
      - Ottinger Foundation, 1986, undated (Box 3)
    - Leadership development: (Box 3)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 3)
      - Campaign for Human Development, 1986, undated (Box 3)
      - Disciples Reconciliation Fund, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
      - Empowerment, 1986-1988, undated (Box 3)
      - Field Foundation, 1982-1986, undated (Box 3)
      - Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education and Hearst proposal and guidelines, 1983-1987,undated (Box 3)
      - Funding exchange, 1986-1987, undated (Box 3)
      - Hearst proposal, 1984-1986 (Box 3)
      - Information, 1984-1986, undated (Box 3)
      - Lutheran Church in America, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
      - Methodist call to prayer, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
      - Poverello Fund, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Roberts, Ann and Smith, Sheri, 1986, undated (Box 3)
      - Sisters of Mercy, 1986 (Box 3)
      - United Methodist Church Call to Prayer Program, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
      - Women's Education Equity Act, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Women's Opportunity Giving Fund, 1983-1986, undated (Box 3)
    - Research: (Box 3)
      - Aetna Life and Casualty, 1984 (Box 3)
      - Fund for Southern Communities, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
      - New World Foundation, 1984 (Box 3)
      - Wellspring Fund, 1984, undated (Box 3)
    - Southeast Women's Employment Coalition: (Box 3)
      - Economics Research Project, 1982-1987, undated (Box 3)
      - Research and Education Program, 1984-1986, undated (Box 3)
    - Tourism: (Box 3)
      - Economic Development Administration, 1985-1988, undated (Box 3)
      - Ecumenical Review, 1987, undated (Box 3)
      - Episcopal Coalition for Human Needs, 1979-1987, undated (Box 3)
      - Levi Strauss Foundation, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Needmor Fund, 1985-1986, undated (Box 3)
      - United Church of Christ: Hunger Action Fund, 1987 (Box 3)
      - United Methodist Women: Food, Land, and Justice Program, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Racism: (Box 3)
    - Black workers, 1983-1986 (Box 3)
    - Hispanics, 1985-1987 (Box 3)
    - Race: General information, 1981-1986, undated (Box 3)
    - Traditional peoples, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Religious sources: Church funding sources, 1980?-1986, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Rural United States: (Box 3)
    - Economic trends, 1981-1986, undated (Box 3)
    - Employment: Women, undated (Box 3)
  - Rural United States: (Box 4)
    - Health, 1980-1985 (Box 4)
    - Women: General, 1977-1982 (Box 4)
  - Service work and workers: (Box 4)
    - Domestic workers, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
    - Fast food industry and workers, undated (Box 4)
    - Food, grocery workers, 1976-1979, undated (Box 4)
    - Health care workers and industry, 1984-1986, undated (Box 4)
    - Service industry: General trends, 1982-1987 (Box 4)
  - Southeast United States: Regional issues: (Box 4)
    - Economic development issues, 1982-1988, undated (Box 4)
    - Economic trends: Notes, 1980-1984, undated (Box 4)
    - High technology in the South, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
    - Southern women, 1979-1985, undated (Box 4)
    - Statistics: Employment, income, poverty, 1940-1984 (Box 4)
  - Southeast Women's Employment Coalition Educational Materials: (Box 4)
    - Women in the Southern Economy: Who Are We?, 1982-1984, undated (Box 4)
    - Economics education models, 1984-1986, undated (Box 4)
    - Homophobia, 1981-1986, undated (Box 4)
    - Lists, ideas, sketches, 1985-1986, undated (Box 4)
    - Speeches, articles, etc., 1985-1986, undated (Box 4)
    - Workshop ideas and materials, 1976-1987, undated (Box 4)
  - States: (Box 4)
    - Alabama: (Box 4)
      - Black community, 1982-1985, undated (Box 4)
      - Statistics, 1982-1983, undated (Box 4)
    - Arkansas, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
    - Florida, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Kentucky: Women, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
    - North Carolina: (Box 4)
      - Economic development, 1981-1985 (Box 4)
      - General information, 1981-1987, (2 folders) (Box 4)
      - History, 1927-1980 (Box 4)
      - Interviews, 1983, undated (Box 4)
      - Poverty, 1970-1983 (Box 4)
      - Statistics, 1964-1984 (Box 4)
    - South Carolina: (Box 4)
      - General Information, 1980-1986 (Box 4)
      - Labor force statistics, 1980-1985 (Box 4)
      - Statistics, 1960-1980 (Box 5)
      - Women's Economic Development Project, 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - West Virginia: (Box 5)
      - Coal industry, 1983-1985 (Box 5)
      - General information, 1976-1984, undated (Box 5)
      - Economic development, 1982-1986, undated (Box 5)
      - Poverty reports, 1982-1984, undated (Box 5)
      - Statistics: (Box 5)
        - Educational, undated (Box 5)
        - Labor force, 1979-1986, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
        - Population and poverty, 1979-1984, undated (Box 5)
  - Textile and apparel industries: (Box 5)
    - Industry structure, 1966 (Box 5)
    - Technology and economic trends, 1983-1985, undated (Box 5)
    - Workforce and union issues, 1930-1986, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Tourism: (Box 5)
    - Hotel industry, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
    - International tourism, 1977-1986, undated (Box 5)
    - Models and resources, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Newsletters, information sources, 1986-1988, undated (Box 5)
    - Retirees and second home development, 1984-1986 (Box 5)
    - States and regions: (Box 5)
      - Florida, 1986 (Box 5)
      - Georgia, 1986 (Box 5)
      - Kentucky, 1987 (Box 5)
      - North Carolina, 1977-1987, undated (Box 5)
      - South Carolina, 1980-1988, undated (Box 5)
      - Virginia, 1988 (Box 5)
      - West Virginia, 1983-1988, undated (Box 5)
      - Western United States, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Unemployment: (Box 5)
    - General, 1969-1986, undated (Box 5)
    - Organizing the unemployed, 1983-1985 (Box 5)
    - Rates, 1982-1987, undated (Box 5)
    - Women, 1979-1985 (Box 5)
  - United States economy: (Box 5)
    - Capital flight and deindustrialization, 1983-1984, undated (Box 5)
    - General trends: Recession and recovery, 1980-1985 (Box 5)
    - Industrial policy, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    - Restructuring, 1981-1987 (Box 5)
  - Wages: (Box 5)
    - Comparable worth, 1981-1986, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Distribution of wealth, 1983-1987, undated (Box 5)
    - Minimum wage, 1980-1988 (Box 5)
    - Pay gap, 1982-1987, undated (Box 5)
    - Wage and income trends, 1981-1986, undated (Box 5)
  - Women: (Box 6)
    - Employment (General): (Box 6)
      - Occupational segregation, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
      - Older women, 1987 (Box 6)
      - Trends, 1973-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6)
      - Women in the workforce: Statistics, 1982-1987, undated (Box 6)
    - International issues: (Box 6)
      - Global assembly line, 1986 (Box 6)
      - United Nations Decade of Women, 1985, undated (Box 6)
      - Women in agricultural production, 1981-1982, undated (Box 6)
      - Women in development, 1975-1987, undated (Box 6)
    - Nontraditional employment: (Box 6)
      - Jobs, 1984-1985, undated (Box 6)
      - Women coal miners, 1980-1981, undated (Box 6)
      - Women in the ministry, 1978-1984, undated (Box 6)
      - Women's Opportunity in Road Construction Project: Highway statistics, 1987, undated (Box 6)
    - Women of color: Racism (Box 6)
      - 1977-1985, undated (Box 6)
      - Afro-American women, 1983-1984, undated (Box 6)
      - Native American women, 1977-1984, undated (Box 6)
      - Women and racism, 1983, undated (Box 6)
- Board and Staff Meetings Series, 1983-1990, undated (bulk 1985-1988) (Box 6)
  Chiefly meeting agendas and minutes. Arranged in chronological order.
  - 1982, Jan.-1986, Mar., (23 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1986, May-1987, (32 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1987, June-1988, Nov., (38 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1988, Nov.-1990, July, (13 folders) (Box 9)
- Office Files Series, 1972-1990, undated (bulk 1983-1988) (Box 9)
  Correspondence, manuals, reports, pamphlets, newsletters, catalogs, financial papers. Also includes Southeast Women's Employment Coalition personnel policies and bylaws. Arranged in alphabetical order by topic. See addition to this series at end of container list.
  - Activities report: (Box 9)
    - 1982-1985 (Box 9)
    - Donations and endorsements: (Box 9)
      - 1979-1987 (Box 9)
      - Mailing list, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Administrative Committee Meeting, 1987 (Box 9)
  - Administrative policy: (Box 9)
    - Decisions, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Transitional period, 1988, Sept.-1989, Jan. (Box 9)
  - Apprenticeships and training law, 1978-1987 (Box 9)
  - Board history, 1983-1986 (Box 9)
  - Board information, 1985-1989 (Box 9)
  - Budget: (Box 9)
    - 1982-1988 (Box 9)
    - Audits and Internal Revenue Service letters, 1984-1987 (Box 9)
    - Expenses, 1983-1987 (Box 9)
  - Child care: Youth Committee, 1984-1988 (Box 9)
  - Conflict resolution workshop, 1987, undated (Box 9)
  - Congressional hearings: Lodging, travel, etc., 1987 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: (Box 9)
    - Board, 1983-1987 (Box 9)
    - External, 1983-1988, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Internal, 1983-1990 (Box 9)
  - Discussion papers: Women and work, 1975-1980, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Employment labor laws, 1983-1986 (Box 9)
  - Five steps to improving productivity, undated (Box 9)
  - Freedom of Information Act, undated (Box 9)
  - Group: Roles, functions, and behaviors, 1971-1984 (Box 9)
  - Guidelines for incorporating a non-profit corporation, undated (Box 9)
  - How to do Newsletters booklet, 1976 (Box 9)
  - How to enter the trades, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Interviewing tool, telephone assessment by Lillian Cleaver, undated (Box 10)
  - Kentucky: (Box 10)
    - 1988, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Aetna insurance, 1983-1989 (Box 10)
    - Blue Collar Women, 1984-1985 (Box 10)
    - Computer complaint, 1986 (Box 10)
    - Copyright registration, 1986 (Box 10)
    - Federation of Child Care Centers loan, 1985 (Box 10)
    - First Security Bank, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Lexington copy products, 1981-1985 (Box 10)
    - Louisville, 1988-1989 (Box 10)
    - Pension/health plans: Quotes, 1986 (Box 10)
    - Public Affairs Research and Communications, Inc.: (Box 10)
      - Activities report disk (Box 10)
      - Speech, Leslie Lilly, undated (Box 10)
      - Southeast Women's Employment Coalition transitional period, 1986 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous business transactions, 1986-1989 (Box 10)
  - Lease/office space, 1988-1990 (Box 10)
  - Mailing list: (Box 10)
    - undated (Box 10)
    - To advertise Women of the Rural South, undated (Box 10)
  - Meetings, miscellaneous, 1986-1988, undated (Box 10)
  - Membership recruiting, undated (Box 10)
  - Midwest Academy: (Box 10)
    - 1977 (Box 10)
    - Organizing handbook, undated (Box 10)
    - Training manual, 1972-1976, (3 folders) (Box 10)
  - Operating evaluation questions, undated (Box 10)
  - Organizing: Grassroots, 1986-1987 (Box 10)
  - Parliamentary procedure, undated (Box 10)
  - Penn Center information, 1972-1986 (Box 10)
  - Personnel policies: (Box 10)
    - 1988 (Box 10)
    - Child care, undated (Box 10)
    - Consultant fees, undated (Box 10)
    - Dependent care, undated (Box 10)
    - Draft, 1982-1985 (Box 10)
    - Insurance, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
    - Manual and bylaws, 1982-1988, (7 folders) (Box 10)
    - Manual, current and past, 1982-1985 (Box 11)
    - Parental leave, 1986-1987 (Box 11)
    - Pay equity, 1987-1988 (Box 11)
    - Per diem expenses, undated (Box 11)
    - Revisions, 1983-1987 (Box 11)
  - Press packet/newspaper clippings, Washington D.C., 1985 press conference, 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Priority issues for Southern women, 1989 (Box 11)